"真是多谢!"
"前往蒙塔克的火车在B站台"
"Montauk train on track B."
2004年情人节  偶然的想法
Random thoughts for Valentine's Day, 2004.
今天是贺卡公司发明的节日
Today is a holiday invented by greeting card companies
"最后一次播报"
Last call
好让人们感觉像废物
to make people feel like crap.
我今天没去上班
I ditched work today.
而是坐上了去蒙塔克的火车
Took a train out to Montauk.
"请到B站台搭乘前往蒙塔克的火车"
"Montauk train boarding on track B."
我不知道原因
I don 't know why.
我不是一个冲动的人
Aah! I'm not an impulsive person.
我想只是今早醒来有些茫然失措
I guess I just woke up in a funk this morning.
我得把车送去修理
I gotta get my car fixed.
你好  辛迪
Hi. Cindy?
我是乔尔  乔尔!
It's Joel. Joel!
听着  我今天感觉不舒服
Listen, I don't feel very well today.
不  我想是食物中毒
No, food poisoning, I think.
这海滩实在是冷死人
It's goddamn freezing on this beach.
二月份的蒙塔克  真是不错  乔尔
Montauk in February Brilliant,Joel.
被撕掉的页
Page is ripped out.
不记得自己撕过
Don't remember doing that.
这好像是我两年来的头一次记录
It appears this is my first entry in two years.
不要过度赞美细沙
Sand is overrated.
它们不过是细小的岩石
It's just tiny, little rocks.
希望我能结识新的伴侣
If only, I could meet someone new.
但我想这样的机会很小
I guess my chances of that happening are some what diminished,
我不敢和眼前这陌生女人 做目光的接触
seeing that I'm incapable of making eye contact with a woman I don't know.
也许我该和内奥米重修旧好
Maybe I should get back together with Naomi.
她很美丽  美丽就是好
She was nice. Nice is good.
她爱过我
She loved me.
为什么我总是爱上每个
Why do I fall in love with every woman I see
对我稍加注意的女人?
who shows me the least bit of attention?
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
-我只是问好  -嗨  你好
-I just said hi. - Hi. Hello. Hi.
我可以坐近些吗?
Okay if I sit closer?
你到哪儿去?
How far are you going?
嗯  洛克威尔中心
Uh, Rockville Center.
不会吧!  我也是!
Get out! Me too!
-真的?  -真巧
Really? What are the odds?
我认识你吗?
Do I know you?
你是不是在巴恩斯・洛贝尔店买过书?
Do you ever shop at Barnes & Noble?
-是的  -那就对了!
Sure. Sure. That's it!
-什么?  -我以前见过你
Yeah? I've seen you, man!
我在那里作售书员已经五年了
Book slave there for, like, five years now.
-啊  我想我可能记得你  -天  是五年吗?
Ah. I would have thought I would've remembered you. Jesus! Is it five years?
可能是头发的缘故
It might be the hair.
-可能什么?  -发型改变了很多
What might? It changes a lot.
我改变了发型的颜色  那就是你没认出我来的原因
The color. That's why you might not recognize me.
-这发型颜色叫"蓝色废墟"  -很对
It's called Blue Ruin, the color. Right. Yeah.
-很时髦的名字  对吧?  -我喜欢
Snappy name, huh? I like it.
这公司所做出的全色系的发型  名字都很时髦
Anyway, this company makes a whole line of colors with equally snappy names.
红色威胁、黄色狂热、绿色革命
Red-- Red Menace, Yellow Fever, Green Revolution.
一定有专门职位来命名这些发型
That'd be a job coming up with those names.
会有那样的工作吗?
You think there could possibly be a job like that?
我是说 总共才有多少种发型颜色呢? 也许十五种吧
I mean how many hair colors could there be? Fifty, maybe.
有人在做这工作
Someone's got that job.
我能想出来的-橙色特工!
Agent Orange! I came up with that one.
我用发型颜色来表明我的个性
I apply my personality in a paste.
噢  我很怀疑
Oh, I doubt that very much.
因为你不认识我  那么
Well, you don't know me, so
你并不了解我  对吧?
you don't know, do you?
对不起  我只是想尽量显得友好些
Sorry. I was just-- I'm trying to be nice.
好的  我明白了
Yeah. I got it.
-顺便提一下  我叫克莱门汀  -我叫乔尔
My name's Clementine, by the way. I'm Joel.
你好  乔尔
Hi,Joel. Hey.
不准取笑我的名字
No jokes about my name.
不  你不会那么做的  你想尽量友好些
Oh, no, you wouldn't do that. You're trying to be nice.
我不知怎样取笑你的名字
I don't know any jokes about your name.
腰浆果狗(卡通片名)
Huckleberry Hound.
我不知道那是什么
I don't know what that means.
你不知道腰浆果狗?  你白痴么?
Huckleberry Hound? What are you nuts?
有人曾这样暗示过
It's been suggested.
我亲爱的 我亲爱的克莱门汀
Oh my darling, oh my darling, Oh my darling Clementine
你已永远离去
You were lost and gone forever
多么抱歉  克莱门汀
Dreadful sorry Clementine
知道了吗?
No?
对不起  但那真是个美丽的名字
I'm sorry. Just-- It's a pretty name, though. It really is nice.
它的意思是  "仁慈"
It's, uh-- It means "merciful."
对吗 仁慈?
Right? Clemency?
虽然看上去不像
Although it hardly fits.
但说真的  我是一个报复心极强的小贱货
I'm a vindictive little bitch, truth be told.
我不会那样想
Gee, I wouldn't think that aboutyou.
-为什么?  -我不知道
Why wouldn't you think that about me? I don't know.
我只是
I just--
我不知道  我只是
I don't know. I just, uh--
你看上去是好人  那
You seem nice, so--
噢  现在我成好人啦?
Oh, now I'm nice?
上帝!  难道你不会用别的形容词汇吗?
Oh, God. Don't you know any other adjectives?
我不需要好
I don't need "nice."
我不想对别人好  也不想别人对我好
I don't need myself to be it, and I don't need anybody else to be it at me.
乔尔?
Joel?
你的名字是乔尔吧?
It's Joel, right?
是的
Yes.
对不起  冲你大喊大叫
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
我今天有些不开心
I'm a little out of sorts today.
我得不好意思的承认
My embarrassing admission is,
我真的喜欢你对我好
I really like that you're nice right now.
我的意思是 我不知道下一时刻自己会喜欢什么
I mean, I can't tell from one moment to the next what I'm gonna like,
但是现在
but right now
我很高兴你对我好
I'm glad you are.
我有很多事情  我也许该
I have so much stuff that, uh, I probably should
-我正在写作  -对不起
Oh! I'm sorry. Okay. I-I'm writing, and--
-不 不用  -没什么
No, no. I just-- Sure. No. That's okay.
我只是得 你知道 这是 好吧
I just have-- You know, this is-- Okay.
保重
- Take care, then.
老天!
Jesus!
我可以送你一程 如果你需要的话
Hi. I could, uh, give you a ride, if you need.
天很冷
It's cold.
好 好的
Yeah. Okay. Yeah. Yeah?
都结霜了
It is frosty.
-你不是在跟踪我吧?  -我没有
You're not a stalker or anything, right? I'm not a stalker.
是你先和我说话的  还记得吗?
You're the one that talked to me. Remember?
那是跟踪守则中最老土的伎俩
That is the oldest trick in the stalker book.
真的吗?  有这本书?
Really? There's a stalker book?
好的  我会读读看
I gotta read that one.
看 我对刚才的疯狂表现感到抱歉  我并不是这样
Look, I'm sorry if I came off sorta nutso. I'm not, really.
没什么  我没想过你是
Oh, it's okay. I didn't think you were.
你想喝一杯吗?
Did you wanna have a drink?
我有很多种酒  我可以
I have lots of drinks, and I could
算了
Never mind.
-对不起 那真傻  真难为情  -不 不 不
Sorry. That was stupid. I'm embarrassed now. No, no, no, no.
晚安  乔尔
Good night,Joel.
两杯蓝色废墟
Two Blue Ruins.
谢谢
Thank you.
喝光它  小子
Drink up, young man.
这样我勾引你就不会惹你反感了
It'll make the whole seduction part less repugnant.
我只是开玩笑!
I'm just kidding!
来吧
Come on.
你有点内向  是吧?
You're kinda closed-mouthed, aren'tyou?
对不起
I'm sorry.
那只是  我的生活很无趣
It's just, you know, my life isn't that interesting.
我去上班  我下班回家
I go to work, I come home.
我不知道有什么好说的
Don't know what to say.
你应看看我的日记
You should read myjournal.
我的意思是  我的生活全是 空白
I mean, it's just blank.
真的?  那让你觉得悲哀或忧虑吗?
Really? Does that make you sad oranxious?
我是说  想到没有好好生活我就觉得忧虑
I mean, I'm always anxious thinking I'm not living my life to the fullest,
可以利用各种可能性
taking advantage of every possibility,
来确保我没有浪费  我所拥有的每一秒
making sure I'm not wasting one second of the little time I have.
-我想过  -是吗?
I think about that. Yeah?
你真是好人
You're really nice.
上帝  我一直忍不住这样说
Ohh! God, I have to stop saying that.
我想嫁给你
I'm gonna marry you.
我知道这一点
I know it.
嗯 好的
Um okay.
乔尔  你哪天应陪我去查尔斯河看看
Joel, you should come up to the Charles with me sometime.
它在每年二月这时都会结冰
It gets frozen this time of year.
-听起来很恐怖  -对
That sounds scary. Exactly.
我会去野餐
I'll pack a picnic.
一个夜晚的野餐  夜晚的野餐感觉与众不同
A night picnic. Night picnics are different.
而我们可以
And, um, we could--
听起来不错
Sounds good.
但我现在该走了
But I-- I should, uh, go. Now.
你应该留下
You should stay.
不  我真的该
No, I really-- I'm-- I--
我明天得早起
I have to get up so early.
我希望你会给我打电话
I would like you to call me.
你会打电话吗?  我会高兴的
Would you do that? I would like it.
我会的
Yes.
当你打电话时祝我情人节快乐!
Wish me a happyValentine's Day when you call!
那会很好的
That'd be nice.
为什么这么久才打来?
What took you so long?
我刚回家
I just walked in.
嗯 你想我吗?
Mm-hmm. You miss me?
奇怪的是  我想你!
Yeah. Oddly enough, I do.
你说"我想你"  我想那就意味着我们结婚了
You said "I do." I guess that means were married.
我想是的
I guess so.
明天晚上好吗?  在冰上渡蜜月
Tomorrow night? Honeymoon on ice?
今年这冰真坚固
It's really solid this time of year.
我不知道
Whoa! I don't know.
来吧
Come on. Come on. Eee!
来吧  来吧  来吧
Come on. Come on, come on.
真美啊!
Oh. So beautiful.
难道不是吗?
Isn't it?
不要走得太过去!
Uh, don't go too fiar.
-你还好吧?  -痛呀!  该死
- Are you okay? - Ouch! Fuck it.
噢  我的屁股!
Ohh! Oh, my ass!
-我想我该走回去  -过来!
I think I should go back. Come on. Come on!
如果冰破了怎么办?
What if it breaks?
什么如果?  你真的这么在意?
- "What if'? Do you really care right now?
请过来!
Come here. Please.
来吧
Come on.
来滑冰吧
Slidy-slidy. Slidy-slidy. Whoa!
-这真好  -我给你看看这个
This is good. Here, let me show you this one thing.
你在干什么?
What Are you doing? Whoa.
来吧
Come on.
我想我听到了破裂声
Think I heard a crack.
不会破裂  也不会断开
It's not gonna crack or break or--
这冰很厚
It's so thick.
给我看看你知道的星座
Show me which constellations you know.
我不知道
I don't know any.
给我看看你知道的
Show me which ones you know.
好吧
Okay.
好的
那是奥斯蒂斯星座
Oh. Here's Osidius.
在哪儿?
Where?
就在那儿  看到了吗?
Right there. See?
那里有一个斜坡和十字状
Sort of a swoop and a cross.
奥斯蒂斯星座
Osidius the Emphatic.
-你在瞎编  对吧?  -没有
You're full of shit. Right? Nope.
就在那儿 斜坡和十字
Osidius is right there. Swoop and cross.
别乱说啦!
Shut the fuck up!
克莱门汀
Clementine.
醒醒
Cock-a-doodle-doo.
抱歉把你叫醒  到你家了
Hey. Sorry to wake you, but we're here.
我能去你家吗?
Can I come over to your house
去睡觉
to sleep?
我太累了
I'm so tired.
好的  当然可以
Okay. Um, yeah. Sure.
让我先去刷牙
Let me get my tooth brush.
什么?
Yes?
-我能帮你吗?  -你的意思是
Can I help you? What do you mean?
我能在什么地方帮你吗?
Can I help you with something?
你在这里干什么?
What arey ou doing here?
我不知道你到底在问什么
I'm not really sure what you're asking me.
谢谢啦
Thanks.
主演 金・凯利
主演 凯特・温莱斯特
片名 《美丽心灵的永恒阳光》
-我们在找159号  -那是什么号码?
We're looking for 159. What number's that?
我不知道那在哪儿?
I don't know where that is.
天  你认为他们会特别标出那号码或至少把那号码放
Jesus Christ, you'd think they,'d light the number, or at least put a number on
-那是他吗?  -我想是
Is that him? I think so.
就是他  等等  那是他
Yeah, that's him. Wait. That's him.
-嗨  乔尔  -弗兰克
Hey, Joel. Frank.
该死!
Oh, shit.
天啊  我情人节收到的唯一贺卡是我老妈送的
Jesus. The only, Valentine's Day, cards I get are from my mother.
我真是悲惨  是吧?
How pathetic is that, huh?
你真走运能拥有克莱门汀 伙计
You're lucky you have Clementine, man.
她很酷
She is way cool.
你和她怎么过情人节呢?
Hey, you got any big Valentine's Day plans with her?
(空白有限公司)
没有.
No.
还有一天就情人节了  做好准备像预定座位什么的
Well, it's only a day away. Better make some reservations or something.
你们不想就在麦当劳过吧?
Don't want to end up at Mickey D's. Right?
浪漫先生!
McRomance!
你想吃些炸薯条吗?
You want some fries with that shake?
我现在得睡觉了  弗兰克
I have to, uh, go to sleep now, Frank.
才八点半
It's 8:30.
帕特里克  别唱了
Patrick, stop it.
还好
Okay. Okay.
开始行动
Showtime at the Apollo.
安静点
Quiet.
乔尔  怎么啦?
Hey, Joel. What's up?
你好  弗兰克
Hi, Frank.
我只从我老妈那儿得到情人节贺卡
I only get Valentine's Day cards from my mom.
我真悲惨 对吧?
How pathetic is that?
你真走运能拥有克莱门汀  乔尔
You're I ucky you have Clementine, Joel.
你和她打算怎样过情人节?
Hey, you got, uh, any, uh, big Valentine's Day plans with her?
没有
No.
还有一天了
It's only a day away.
做好准备  像预定座位什么的
Better make a reservation or something.
不要就在麦当劳过了
Don't wanna end up at Mickey D's.
不!
Oh, no!
离情人节还有三天  我想尽快和好
Yes! Valentine's Day is three goddamn day's away! I want it resolved.
我想主动与她和好
I'm willing to be the one to resolve it.
于是我给她打电话  她竟然换了号码
So I call her and she's changed her number.
所以我到怪异阁买礼物送她
So I walked over to Antic Attic, you know to get her something.
我想这会奏效的  给她一个早点的情人节惊喜
I thought I'd go over to work give her an early valentine Day.
你不会相信
You won't bel ieve it.
她在那儿
She's there with
和那个家伙在一起!  很年轻的家伙!
this guy, this really young guy.
她看着我的样子  好像她根本不认识我
And she looks at me like she doesn't even know who I am.
对不起?
Excuse me?
你想找些什么书  先生?
Can I help you find something, sir?
嗨  甜心
Hey, Clem-ato.
帕特里克!  宝贝男孩
Patrick! Baby boy.
-你来这里干什么  宝贝?  -我给你带来惊喜
Whatyou doing here, baby? Just came to surprise you.
如果你想要书就告诉我  先生  你看上去不错
Let me know if you need something, sir. You look good.
-你怎么样?  -很好  也很累
How are you? Pretty, good. Pretty, bored. Pretty, tired.
我想要你衣服里的东西  不错
I so want what's in your suit. Oh, good.
为什么?
Why?
她为什么那样对我?
Why would she do that to me?
有人想吸大麻吗?
Hey, does anybody want a joint?
罗布  别管那个了
Oh, God, Rob, give it a rest.
上帝啊  她在惩罚我
Oh, God. She's punishing me.
-我知道  -因为我说了实话
I know, honey. For being honest.
-这真糟糕  -我该直接去她家
It's horrible. I should just go to her house.
不!  不  你不会想去那儿的
No! No, no, no. You don't wanna go there, man. You don't wanna go there.
下去  那太
Get off. It's too--
对
Right. Yeah.
我不想她看到我这么绝望
I don't want to seem desperate.
乔尔  为什么你不把这看着一个信号呢?
Joel, why don't you just see this as a sign,
一个彻底分手的信号
make a clean break. Right?
对吗?
Right?
好吧  乔尔 老实说
All right, Joel, look man seriously.
-罗布!  -事情是这样
Rob! Here's the deal.
不要这样  罗布  你要干什么?  不  不要
Don't do that. Rob, what are you doing? No, no, no, no.
那你有什么好建议呢  卡丽?
What's your fucking suggestion, Carrie?
你有什么完美的解决办法?
What's your brilliant reasoned solution?
你会把我们卷进来  这不关我们的事
You're gonna make this about our shit now? This isn't about us.
对  这不关我们的事  这关乔尔的事  他已经长大了
I agree. It's not about us. It's about Joel, who's an adult. Okay?
不再是"卡丽妈咪"的小孩子
Not Mama Carrie's kid.
你在说  你自己去洗!
-What are you? -That's your laundry!
太好了  好极了
That's great. That's good.
原来是这样
Okay.
亲爱的艾克姆夫妇
克莱门汀・克罗斯基从她的记忆中抹去了乔尔
请别再向她提起他们以前的关系
谢谢  空白有限公司
-这是什么?  -我不知道  是做什么研究的地方吧
What is it? I don't know. It's some place that does a thing.
早安  这是空白有限公司
Good morning. Lacuna.
不  抱歉  那报价过了元旦已经到期了
No, I'm sorry. That offer expired after the new year.
当然  我们可以给你安排
Yeah, sure. We can fit you in.
第五位怎么样?
How about on the fifth?
星期三  好的  你可以拼读出来吗?
That's a Wednesday. All right, great. Could you spell that please?
好的  请告知你的日间电话
Okay, and we'll need a daytime phone number.
好  祝你今天愉快!  再见
Great. Have a nice day. See you then.
你有什么事?
May I help you?
-我是乔尔・巴瑞斯  -什么?
I 'm Joel Barish. Excuse me?
我是乔尔・巴瑞斯  我和米R维克医生有个约见
I 'm Joel. Barish. I have an appointment with Dr.Mierzwiak.
-你可以填这个表单吗?  -我只想和他谈一谈
-Here. Could you please fill this out? -I just want to talk to him.
-你仍得先填这表单  先生  -真的吗?
You still need to fill the form out, sir. Really?
谢谢
-Thank you. -Great.
我没有钢笔
I don't have a pen.
在那儿有一支
There's a pen right there.
早安  空白有限公司
Good morning. Lacuna. Oh.
那个报价在元旦后过期了
That offer. That's done now. That expired after the new year.
巴瑞斯先生
Mr. Barish?
你今天好吧?
How are we today?
不是很好
Not too good actually.
天  斯坦!
Oh, my God! Stan!
-对不起  我只是在  -我在工作
Sorry. Sorry, I was just I'm working!
对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
-这里  医生  -谢谢
Here, Doctor. Thank you.
你不应该看到这个
You should not have seen this.
真对不起
I apologize.
这是开玩笑  对吗?  这是克莱门汀她
This is a hoax, right? I mean, this is Clem--
-我向你保证  -不是的
I am sure you. No.
这算什么
There's no such thing as this.
瞧  巴瑞斯先生  客户档案是保密的
Look, our files are confidential, Mr.Barish,
我不能把它们给你看
so I can't show you evidence.
这样说吧  克罗斯基活得很不快乐
Suffice it to say that Miss, Miss Kruczynski was not happy,
她想要新的生活
and she wanted to move on.
我们提供了可行性
We provide that possibility.
克罗斯基活得很不快乐  她想要新的生活
"Miss Kruczynski was not happy and wanted to move on.
我们提供了可行性
We provide that possibility."
那是什么鬼话?
What the hell is that?
我是她遇到过的最好的男人
Nicest guy she everwent out with.
天  罗布!  别敲了!
God, Rob! Give it a rest!
没什么
It's okay. It's all right.
卡丽  我正在作鸟屋
Carrie, I am making a bird house.
我怎么说呢?  乔尔  你了解克莱门汀  她就是这样
What can Isay, Joel? You know Clementine. She's like that.
做事冲动
She's impulsive.
她一时兴起就想将你彻底忘记
She decided to erase you almost as a lark.
一时兴起?
A lark.
为什么?  为什么?  为什么你要那样做?
Why? Why? Why? Why did you do that?
等等  等等!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
对不起  医生  他硬闯进来
I'm sorry, Doctor. He just barged right in here.
-好吧  我想清除我的记忆
Okay. I want it done.
-我告诉他在情人节前我们是最忙的
I told him pre-Valentine's Day is our busy time.
-没事的  玛丽  -但有人还等着
that's okay, Mary. -But there are people waiting.
巴瑞斯先生  如果你愿意进来
Mr. Barish, if you'd like to come inside.
-玛丽  你能送走吴女士吗?  -当然可以
And Mary, if you could take care of Mrs Woo. Yes, of course.
我们要你做的头一件事  巴瑞斯先生
the first thing we need you to do, Mr. Barish,
就是回家
is to go home.
寻找所有与克莱门汀有关的事物
and collect everything you own that has some association with Clementine.
所有的
Anything.
我们会用这些事物在你的大脑里
And we'll use these items to
建立一个与克莱门汀有关的映象
create a map of Clementine in your brain.
所以我们需要相片、衣物、礼品
So we'll need, photos, clothing, gifts,
像她送给你的书  你们俩一起购买的CD
books she may have bought you CDs, you may have bought together,
日记
journal entries.
我们想清空你的家
We want to empty your home.
我们想从你生命中清除克莱门汀
We want to empty your life of Clementine.
在那个映象被建立后
And after the mapping is done,
技术员今晚会到你家作记忆消除术
our technicians will do the erasing in your home tonight.
这样  你第二天清晨醒来时
That way, when you awake in the morning,
你发现自己躺在床上  就像什么也没发生过一样
you'll find yourself in your own bed as if nothing had happened.
一个全新的生活等待着你
a new life waiting you.
别作白日梦  伙计!
Wake up, buddy!
对不起  索贝尔夫人
No, I'm sorry. Mrs.Sobel.
你不能一个月做三次记忆消除术
You can't have the procedure done three times in one month.
这是我们的制度  你好吗  巴瑞斯先生?
Well, it's just not our policy. How are you today, Mr. Barish?
你好  我还在线
Hello. I'm right here.
我知道这很紧急  我们会尽力把你
I know it's an emergency, and we'll do everything we can
安排到三月份头一个
We can fit you in on the first of March.
也许你该跟医生说说
Maybe you could talk to the doctor, and he--
好吧  我们就这样约定了
All right, so let's make an appointment.
你星期几来?
What day would you like to come in this week?
-巴瑞斯先生  -医生今下午真的很忙
Mr. Barish. he's really busy this afternoon.
也许明天十二点一刻比较好
Maybe tomorrow would be better. Around 12:15? Can you do that?
因为二月有情人节  所以我们忙得够呛
February is very busy for us because of Valentine's Day.
这是斯坦・范恩
This is Stan Fink,
我们最好的技术人员之一
one of ourmost experienced andskilled technicians.
他今晚为你做消除术
He'll be handling your case tonight.
很高兴认识你  巴瑞斯先生
Great to meet you, Mr. Barish.
我叫乔尔・巴瑞斯
My name is Joel Barish,
我来这儿消除对克莱门汀・克罗斯基的记忆
and I'm here to erase Clementine Kruczynski.
很好  现在告诉我关于克莱门汀的事
Very good. Now tell me about Clementine.
嗯 我
Uh, I was
本来和另一个女人一起生活  她叫内奥米
Living with this woman, Naomi,
几年前
uh, a couple years ago,
我的朋友罗布和卡丽请我们去一个海滩聚会
and my friends Rob and Carrie invited us to this party at the beach.
我不喜欢聚会
I don't like parties.
内奥米不能去  但我去了
Naomi couldn't go, but I went
而且遇到了克莱门汀
and I met Clementine.
对不起
I 'm sorry.
让我们从你最近的回忆开始
Let's start with your most recent memories
然后慢慢向以前删除
and work back wards from there, more or less.
我们的每一段记忆中
There's an emotional core
都会有一个感情核心
to each of our memories,
当这个核心被清除掉时  相应的记忆会缓慢消失
and when you eradicate that core it starts its degradation process.
明早你醒来时
By the time you wake up in the morning,
相应的记忆就会消失无踪
all the memories we've targeted will have withered and disappeared,
就像快醒时做的梦一样
as in a dream upon waking.
有损伤大脑的危险吗?
Is there any risk of brain damage?
从技术角度讲
Well, uh, technically speaking,
这过程本身就是对大脑的伤害
the procedure is brain damage,
但只相当于一场宿醉
but it's on a parwith a night of heavy drinking.
你不会有事的
Nothing you'll miss.
舒服吗?
Comfortable?
巴瑞斯先生  我们现在做的是生成你的脑部图
What we're doing here Mr. Barish is actually creating a map of your brain.
好  我们开始吧
Okay, let's getstarted.
如果你想今晚就做的话  我们有些准备工作要做
If we want to get this procedure under way tonight. We have some work to do.
巴瑞斯先生  我要你对这些物体作出反应
I want you to react to these objects Mr. Barish, if you will.
这里面有一个好故事.
There's a good story behind this one.
巴瑞斯先生  我会得到比较准确的情感读数
Actually, Mr. Barish, I'll get a much better emotional readout.
如果你只在脑海里描述
If you refrain from any sort of verbal description of the items.
所以把集中精力来回忆
Just try to focus on the memories.
-对不起  -没什么
Oh. Sorry. Okay.
健康活性集中在那儿 健康读数很好
Healthy activity up there again. Healthy readouts Very good.
另一件物体
-Here's another object. -That's so.
下一件
Next item. Okay.
"土豆头"
Potato head.
下一件
-Next item. Okay. -
集中精力去回忆  帕特里克  帮帮我
Just focus on the memories. Patrick, do me a fiavor.
-帕特里克  帮帮我好吗?  -好的
Patrick, do me a fiavor, will you? Yeah.
你能检查下稳压器吗?
Can you check the voltage regulator? What do we got there?
-电压看来合适  -真的吗?
-voltage looks fine. Really?
我这里不太清楚
Well, I'm not wiping as clean as I like here.
技术上讲  这个过程就是大脑损伤
Well, technically, the procedure is brain damage.
请检查一下电路连接
Check the connections, please.
你在这里
Oh, there you are.
为什么我?  我不能理解我所看到的
Why am I? I don't understand what I'm looking at.
为什么我站在这儿而
Why am I standing here and--
天  幻觉记忆!
Oh, my God. Dejavu.
一切似曾相识!  这太
Dejavu. This is so--
好  那让我们开始吧  如果我们想今晚就做的话
All right, we should get started. If we're gonna get the procedure.
那我们现在有些准备工作要做
under way tonight, we have some work to do.
我已经进入自己的回忆  对吧?
I'm in my head already, aren't I?
我想是这样的  这是对的
I suppose so. Uh, this is about right.
这就是  这就是记忆清除看上去的样子
This is what it This is what it would look like.
很好
Very good.
结束后我们会清除这些物品
We'll dispose of these mementos when we're done here.
以后你就不会因为他们为什么
That way you won't be confused later by their unexplainable presence
在你家里而困惑了
in your home.
-帕特里克?  -什么?
Patrick? Yeah?
帕特里克  你能检查  帕特里克?
Patrick, can you check-- Patrick?
-我看到自己声音的读数  -帕特里克?
-I'm getting some sort of readout of my own voice. Patrick? Patrick?
-为什么这么多电线?  -有很多设备
-Why are there so many wires? -A lot of equipment.
-有作用吗?  -你确信你正确安装了这些设备吗?
-Does that help? -Are you sure you set that thing up properly?
-好点了吗?  -今天怎么样  巴瑞斯先生?
-How's that? -How are you today, Mr. Barish?
-我们在这儿  巴瑞斯先生  -好点了
There we are, Mr. Barish. That's better.
-我不知道自己是否喜欢这样  -我也许该试试这样
-I don't know if I like this. -Think I might try this then.
快完成了
We're almost done now.
日记的价值无法衡量
Journal. That would be invaluable.
我今晚遇到了一个人  我不知该做些什么
"I met someone tonight. I don't know what to do.
她叫克莱门汀  她很漂亮
Her name is Clementine, and she's amazing. "
什么?  小心点!  退回去!
What? What? Come on! Careful! Step back!
放松些!
Just take it easy.
好的
That's fine.
不要伤害到他了
Let's not roach the guy.
好的  你调好了
All right, you got that one.
-这里像垃圾堆对吧?  -这是公寓房  帕特里克
This place is sort of a dump, don't you think? It's an apartment, Patrick.
帕特里克
Patrick.
那好  不像垃圾堆  但就像一个未赋予灵感的荒原
Well, not a dump then but sorta plain. Uninspired.
还有一股霉臭味
And there's sort of a stale smell.
帕特里克 我们能不能不管这些?
Patrick, can we just please get through this?
-我们还要过漫长的一夜 -好的
We got a very long night ahead of us. Come on. Yeah.
这是我上次看到你的情景
This is the last time I saw you.
现在是凌晨三点
It's 3:00.
我把你的车弄坏了
I kind a sorta wrecked your car.
酒后驾车了吗?
Were you driving drunk?
真是悲惨
It's pathetic.
我是有一点醉
I was a little tipsy.
但别说我悲惨!
Don't call me pathetic.
这就是悲惨
Well, it is pathetic.
-还真他妈不负责任  你可能撞死了人
I t's fucking i rresponsible. Could've killed somebody.
-你也许已经撞死人了  我们该看看新闻?
Maybe you did kill somebody. Should we turn on the news and see?
-也许我该查查看是否有小孩或小动物被撞死?
Should I check the grill to see if there's any children or small animals?
我没有撞死人!
I didn't kill anybody!
那只是个凹痕  约尔  你像个老妇人一样嗦
It's just a fucking dent, Joel. You're like an old lady or something.
你像个什么样?
Well, what are you like?
-一个酒鬼!  -一个酒鬼?
A wino? A wino?
天  你是从五十年代来的吗?
Jesus, Are you from the 50s or something?
酒鬼?
A wino?
老实说吧  乔伊
Face it, Joely.
你发火是因为我今晚很晚都没回来
You're freaked out because I was out late without you,
在你的小脑袋里
and in your little wormy brain
你尽力想发现她是不是和别人做爱了?
you're trying to figure out did she fuck someone tonight?
不 克莱
No, see, Clem,
我想你和别人做爱了
I assume you fucked someone tonight.
不然别人怎么会喜欢你?
Isn't that how you get people to like you?
我道歉  好吗?
I'm sorry. Okay?
克莱  我不是有意的
Clem, I didn't mean it. All right?
-克莱  -钥匙还你!
Clem? Your key's.
-我只是  -我不再需要它们了
-I was just I won't need them any more.
有些烦心、生气  我也不知道自己怎么啦
Angry or annoyed or something, I don't know.
克莱?
Clem?
完成了
Got it.
玛丽今晚会过来
Mary's coming over tonight.
只是想让你知道
Just thoughtyou'd wanna know.
我喜欢玛丽  我喜欢她看我们  但我不觉得她喜欢我
I like Mary. I like when she comes to visit. I just don't think she likes me.
她喜欢你  得了吧
She likes you okay.
所以我也许该把女友叫来  我现在有女友了
Maybe I should invite my girlfriend over. I have a girlfriend now.
我告诉过你我有女友了吗?
Do whateveryou want. Did I tell you I have
Did I tell you I have a new girlfriend?
我们得把精力集中在工作上  帕特里克
We gotta focus here, Patrick.
问题是
Yeah, the thing is
我们的处境有点怪异
our situation  is a little weird.
我女友的情况
My girlfriend situation.
我确信是这样
I'm sure it is.
你一定是开玩笑
You gotta be
克莱  让我送你回家吧
Clem, let me drive you home.
从我面前消失掉!  该死!
Get out of my face, faggot!
看那边!  这里在倒塌
Look at it out here! It's all falling apart!
我在忘掉你  我很高兴这样做!
I'm erasing you, and I'm happy!
是你先这样对我的!
You did it to me first!
我不敢相信你竟然这样对我!  该死!
I can't believe you did this to me. Goddamn it.
克莱!  你听到了吗?
Clem! Can you hear me?
到明天早上  我就会彻底忘了你!
By morning you'll be gone!
真是这狗屁爱情的完美结局!
The perfect ending to this piece-of-shit story!
一个女孩被我吸引会有问题吗?  有问题吗?
Is there something wrong with a girl being attracted to me? Is that a problem?
不  那很有趣
No, I think it's funny.
你觉得我和这家伙哪个更好看?
So, who do you think's better-looking me or this guy?
帕特里克 我们集中精力做好工作
Patrick, let's focus buddy.
记得我们上星期做过的那个女孩么?
Remember that girl we did last week?
带着土豆的女孩?
The one with the potatoes?
-那个女孩?  -是他的女友
That girl? That's this guy's girl.
是的
Right. Yeah.
曾经是  我们小心点
Was. We took care of that.
那晚我有点爱上她了
I kind a fell in love with her that night.
什么?  你这
What? You little fuck
-怎么?  -她毫无知觉
What? She was unconscious, man.
她很漂亮而且
Well, she was beautiful, and
我偷了她的内裤
I stole a pair ofher panties as well.
-天!  -怎么?
Jesus! What?
那不是
It's not like--
-我是说那些内裤很干净
I mean, they were clean and all.
不要跟我说  我不想听这些狗屁
Don't tell me this stuff, man! I don't wanna hear this shit!
-是干净的  -不  别说啦
They,were clean! What? D-Don't! Stop!
-好的  -我们还有工作要做
Okay. All right! We got work to do.
把那些纸给我
Give me my papers.
还有些事
There's more.
那天我们做完她的手术后
After we did her,
我去了她工作的地方并和她约会
I kind of went to where she works and asked her out.
你作了什么?
You what?
天!  帕特里克
Jesus. Patrick!
你知不知道这样
Do you have any idea
没有职业道德?
how unethical?
不会吧
It's not really that bad.
看看你的表情  怎么啦?
What? Get that look off your face. What's wrong?
帕特里克!  你偷了这女孩的内裤
Patrick, you stole a girl's panties!
有人在这里
There's someone here.
他偷了你的内裤
He stole your underwear.
鬼影都没看见
I don't see anyone.
乔尔?
Joel?
我的鞋子在哪里?
Where are my boots?
你为什么给我毒药?  你不懂英文吗?
Why, are you showing me poisons? Can't you understand English?
药剂  我说的是药剂
"Potions" I said. Potions.
请给我爱情药剂
Love potion, please.
我真他妈吓得直起鸡皮疙瘩!
I'm fucking crawling out of my skin!
我该把你一个人甩在跳蚤市场
Should've left you at the flea market.
要做的第一件事是
First thing to do is--
往杯中撒用鲸鱼心脏做的粉末
sift in a cup of powdered whale heart.
想走了吗?
Wanna go?
我想要个小孩
I want to have a baby.
我们以后再谈这个吧
Let's talk about it later.
不要  我想要个小孩
No! I want to have a baby.
我想我们还没准备好
I don't think we're ready.
是你没准备好
You're not ready.
克莱  你真的认为你能照顾好小孩?
Clem, do you really think you could take care of a kid?
什么?
What?
我不想在这儿谈这个
I don't wanna talk about it here.
我听不见  我从来不知道你他妈的说些什么
I can't hear you. I can never the fuck understand what you're saying.
-我不想谈这个  -不要这么小声!
I don't wanna talk about this! Fucking ventrilo quist!
-就要谈!  -我不想
We're fucking gonna talk about it! I don't want to--
你不能在那样说我后  还说你不想再谈了!
You can't just say something like that and say you don't wanna talk about it!
-对不起  克莱  -我会当一个好母亲的
I'm sorry, Clem. I'd make a fucking good mother!
我喜欢小孩子  我聪明又富有创意
I love children, I'm creative and smart,
我会当好母亲的!
and I'd make a fucking great mother!
是你  乔尔!  是你不能成什么事
It's you,Joel. It's you who can't commit to anything!
-这被清除了!  -你不知道你有多么幸运我看上了你
It's going! You have no idea how lucky you are I'm interested in you!
也许我们该在这里分手了  约尔!
Maybe I should end this right here, Joel!
-把你和愚蠢的服装珠宝一起甩在跳蚤市场
Leave you at the flea market with this stupid costume jewelry!
-清除了  这段回忆是垃圾
-It's done. This is crap.
-也许你能找把古董摇椅好去死在上面
Maybe you could find yourself an antique rocking chair to die in!
-所有的这些痛苦和迷惑
-All the pain, confusion
-你好  帕特里克  -你好  玛丽  还好吗?
-Hi, Patrick. -Hi, Mary. How's it goin'?
-你好  -天真冷
Hey, you. Oh, it's freezing outside.
-我们做得还不错吧?  -是的
Find us okay? Yeah.
-嗯  -真亲热!
Mmm. Hot!
可怜的家伙
Poor guy.
有真正的饮料喝吗?
Don't you have anything real to drink?
我们真的还未检查过
Uh, we haven't really checked yet.
-帕特里克?
Patrick?
让我来吧
Let me do the honors.
玛丽讨厌我
Mary hates me.
我从不讨女人的欢心
Never really had much luck with the ladies.
也许你该停止偷她们的内裤
Maybe if you stop stealing their panties.
斯坦  斯坦
Stan. Stan.
-还有更多事  -别说了!
There's more. No!
-是的  -不!
Yes. No!
你不想要酒吧 帕特里克?
You didn't want any, did you, Patrick?
-不要  没什么  -等等
Uh, no, that's okay. Wait.
祝福那些健忘的人吧  因为他们战胜了自己过去的错误
"Blessed are the forgetful for they get the better even of their blunders."
尼采的《超越善恶》
That's Nietzsche. Beyond Good and Evil.
我从"巴特利R" 中摘来的
I found it in my Bartlett's.
什么是"巴特利R" ?
What's your Bartlett's?
那是一本语录  帕特里克
It's a quote book, Patrick.
充满各种名言警句
It's a book of quotations.
我想医生有一天也会上"巴特利R" 的
I think Howard will be in Bartlett's one day.
-肯定  -医生他说的都是名言
Definitely. Howard is pure Bartlett's.
上帝
God!
我们这样会吵醒他吗?
Can you wake him up?
不会
You can't wake him up.
你什么都不跟我讲  乔尔
You don't tell me things, Joel.
我是一本打开的书
I'm an open book.
我什么都告诉你
I tell you everything.
甚至是每一件丢人的事
Every damn embarrassing thing.
你不信任我
You don't trust me.
不断说话并不是必要的交流方式
Constantly talking isn't necessarily communicating.
我没有那样做
I don't do that.
我想了解你更深
I want to know you.
我没有不断说话!
I don't constantly talk. Jesus!
你必须把有些事拿出来分享  乔尔
People have to share things, Joel.
那才是亲密无间
That's what intimacy is.
你那样对我说  真让我生气
I'm really pissed thatyou said that to me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
只是我的生活很无趣
It just really just isn't that interesting.
我想看看你一直在写的备忘录
I wanna read some of those journals you're constantly scribbling in.
你在里面写了什么  如果你不再有想法、激情
What do you write in there if you don't have any thoughts or passions
或爱的话?
or love?
2003年11月19日
November 19, 2003.
又在中餐馆进餐
Dinner at Kang's again.
我们像在这餐馆中的可怜伴侣们吗?
Are we like those poor couples
你为他们感到难过
you feel sorry for in restaurants?
我们都是在进餐的行尸走肉吗?
Are we the dining dead?
我受不了我们那样想别人
I can't stand the idea of us being a couple people think that about.
我喜欢那样
I like that.
鸡肉好吃吗?
How's the chicken?
好吃
Good.
-再来点?  -不要了  谢谢
More? No. No. Thank you.
她会喝醉然后变得愚笨
She's gonna be drunk and stupid now.
你能帮个忙
Hey, would you do me a favor
把你洗澡时留在肥皂上的  脏头发弄干净吗?
and clean the goddamn hair off the soap when you're done in the shower?
-好的  -那有一点
Yeah. It's really
-恶心  -恶心
- Gross. - gross.
-那只是  -讨厌的
-It's just -Repulsive.
讨厌的
It's repulsive.
帕特里克  我们能不能专心完成这个?
Patrick, can we get through this?
帕特里克
Patrick.
嗨  橘子
Hey, Tangerine.
帕特里克  是你
Oh, Patrick, it's you.
我现在很痛苦
I'm so miserable right now.
-为什么?  出了什么事?  -我不知道
-Why? What's wrong? -I don 't know.
-什么?  -我感到非常迷惑
-Excuse me? -I'm so confused!
我能帮你找什么书吗  先生?
Can I help you fiind something, sir?
迷惑?  你对什么感到迷惑  一切都好啊
Confused? What are you confused about? Everything's fine.
宝贝  过来
Baby, come here.
你在害怕什么?
Scared of what?
-你爱我吗?  -当然爱
Do you love me? of course I do.
系统的自我帮助区在哪里?
Where's the self-help section?
你认为我丑吗?
Do you think I'm ugly?
不  你很漂亮
No! You're beautiful!
-也许我该过来  -不  不
Maybe I should come over. No, no.
我不知道  我现在一团糟  帕特里克
I don't know. I'm a mess, Patrick.
让我来吧  我会让你高兴
Well, just let me come over. I'll cheer you up.
好的
Okay.
斯坦  我能离开一会儿吗?  我女友真的不高兴了
Stan, can I leave for a while? My girlfriend's really upset.
我们正在清除这可怜人的记忆中
We're right in the middle of erasing this poor man's--
让他走吧  斯坦!
Let him go, Stan!
让他走吧  我来帮忙
Let him go. I'll help.
看到了吗?  这能有多难?
See? How hard can it be?
-她讨厌我  她想我离开  -那走吧
-She hates me. She wants me to go. -Go.
好的  我这就来  柑橘
All right. I'll be right over, Tangerine.
你喜欢吗?
You like?
不错!
Oh, man!
用来配我的运动衫
I matched my sweatshirt exactly.
-哈 我喜欢 -真的?
-I like it. -You do?
你看上去像个柑橘
You look like a tangerine. Ohh!
克莱门氏小柑橘  汁多!
"Clemen-teen" the tangerine. Juicy!
-而且无核  -我喜欢这称呼
-And seedless. -I like that.
我喜欢柑橘
I like tangerines!
想看我学鸭叫吗?
Can you see me doing ducks?
-柑橘  -约尔  鸭子
Tangerine. Joel. Ducks. Quack-quack.
-他怎么知道这称呼?  -谁知道?
-How does he know to call you that? -How did who know?
-噢  天啊!  克莱?  -这很酷
-Oh, my God. Clem? -This is pretty,cool.
他们称呼自己为
That's what they called themselves.
"撞击" 他们是唯一重要的乐队
The Clash--the only band that mattered.
他们的名字是有含义的
They called themselves that for a reason.
-真是惊异啊  不是吗?  -社会正气
-It's amazing, isn't it? -Like social justice
是的  彻底的了不起
Yeah, it's totally incredible.
我在说医生为这世界所作的
What Howard gives to the world.
是的
Yeah.
让人们能重新开始
To let people begin again.
这真美丽
It's beautiful.
就像看着一个婴儿  如此纯洁、自由和单纯
You look at a baby, and it's so pure and so free and so clean.
成年人的生活真是充满悲哀
And adults are like this mess of sadness
和恐惧
and phobias.
而医生改变了这一切
Howard just makes it all go away.
天啊!
Oh, my,God.
-宝贝  怎么啦?  -我不知道  我不知道!
-Baby, what's going on? -I don't know. I don't know!
我感到迷失、害怕
I'm lost, I'm scared,
我感觉自己好像在消失
I feel like I'm disappearing.
-消失?  -我皮肤开始松弛!  我在变老!
-Disappearing? -My skin's coming off!. I'm getting old!
-一切对我好像都没意义  -你没在变老
-Nothing makes any sense to me! -You're not getting old.
-一切好像都没意义  -噢 柑桔
-Nothing makes any sense. Nothing makes any sense. -Ohh, Tangerine.
一切好像都没意义
Nothing makes any sense.
-一切好像都没意义  -没事的  没事的
-Nothing makes any sense, Patrick. It's okay. It's okay.
我们去跳舞吧? 你想和我一起去蒙塔克吗?
Hey, let's go out dancing. You wanna go out to Montaukwith me?
-蒙塔克?
-Montauk?
-不!  和我去波士顿  -当然  下个星期末去
-No! Come up to Boston with me. -Sure. We can go next weekend.
不  就现在  我必须得去
No, no. Now. Now. I have to go now.
我现在必须去看结冰的查尔斯河
I have to see the frozen Charles now.
你好  这是乔尔家
Hi, it's Joel.
请在听到信号后留言  我会回复的
Leave a message after the beep and I'll get back to you.
斯坦  快接听
Pick up! Pick up, man!
等等 等一等
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
喂  什么事?
Hello? Yeah, what's up?
我和这老女士有些问题要处理
I got into a little situation with the old lady.
你能一个人处理那里的事吗?  伙计  真抱歉
Can you handle things tonight alone? I'm really sorry, man.
别担心  伙计  一切都在我控制之中
Don't worry about it. I got it under control, man.
-他现在处于自动清除程序之中
He's pretty much on autopilot right now anyway.
-谢谢你  斯坦  我欠你的情
-Thanks, Stan. I owe you big-time.
伙计  我得挂了
Dude, I gotta go. I gotta go.
查尔斯河
Charles.
来吧  查尔斯河
Come on, Charles.
"你和我在查尔斯河上 我想现在就死去 克莱"
"Look! You and me on the Charles River. I could die right now, Clem.
"我真的很快乐 以前从未如此感受 我现在就在"
I'm just happy. I've never felt that before. I'm just exactly where I want"
-我好兴奋! -我也很兴奋!
-I'm so excited. -I'm excited too!
把这个
I got you this
-什么?  -送给你
What? thing, um--
情人节快乐
Happy early Valentine's Day.
是什么?
What is it?
我不知道  打开看看
I don't know. Open it up.
这太棒了!
It's gorgeous!
-你喜欢吗?  -是的  正合我口味
-You like it? -Yeah. It's just my taste. Really.
我还从未和送我喜欢珠宝的人出去约会
I've never gone out with a guy who bought me a piece of jewelry I liked.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-走吧  -好的
-Let's go. -Okay.
-乔伊?  -什么  柑桔?
Joely? Yeah, Tangerine?
我丑吗?
Am I ugly?
当我还是小孩时  我觉得自己很丑
When I was a kid, I thought I was.
真不敢相信我已这么多愁善感了
Can't believe I'm crying already.
有时我认为人们不知道  小孩是多么的孤独
Sometimes I think people don't understand how lonely,it is to be a kid.
就像你感到自己很渺小
Like you don't matter.
所以我八岁时
So, I'm eight
我拥有这些玩具
and I have these toys,
这些洋娃娃
these dolls.
我最喜欢一个很丑的女洋娃娃  我叫她克莱门汀
My fiavorite is this ugly girl doll who I call Clementine.
我不停的对她大喊
And I keep yelling at her:
"你不能这么丑!  变漂亮! "
"You can't be ugly! Be pretty!"
这很奇怪
It's weird.
就像如果我可以把她变漂亮
Like if i can transform her,
那我也会魔术般的变漂亮
I would magically, change too.
你很漂亮!
You're pretty.
乔伊  永远不要离开我
Joely, don't ever leave me.
你很漂亮  很漂亮  很漂亮
Pretty. Pretty. Pretty. Pretty.
米R维克医生  求你让我保留这段回忆
Mierzwiak, please let me keep this memory..
就这一段
Just this one.
我不想拖着你  来吧!
I don't wanna hold your hand. Come on.
停下
Stop it!
我想现在就死去  克莱
I could die right now, Clem.
我真的很
I'm just
高兴
happy.
我从未如此感受
I've never felt that before.
我现在就在
I'm just exactly
我一直想去的地方
where I wanna be.
克莱?
Clem?
我想停下来!
I wanna call it off.
我得想办法告诉他们
I'll give you a sign.
我想停下来!
I wanna call it off!.
你听到了吗?  我无法忍受了!
Can you hear me? I don't want this anymore!
我想停下来!
I wanna call it off!.
"你不是无事可做"
"When you ain't got nothing to do"
"我想我会娶你"
"I think I'll marry.you"
有人听到了吗?
Is anybody there?
-克莱门汀?  -乔尔!
Clementine? Joel?
-克莱  -乔伊?
Clement-- Joely?
-克莱!  -乔尔?
Clem! Joel?
克莱!
Clem!
-怎么啦?  -我们得离开
-What? -We gotta go. We gotta go.
-什么? 去哪儿? -我想到阻止这事的办法
-What? Where? -I have an idea of how to stop this.
阻止什么?
Stop what?
-乔伊  -来吧  克莱
Joely. Come on, Clem.
-闻闻我的腋窝!  -不要!
-Smell my armpit! Smell my armpit! -No!
-不要胳肢我!  不要逼我闻你  -闻我的私处
-Don't tickle me! Don't make me smell you. -Smell my pits!
-不要  -好的
-No. -Good.
集中精神  克莱
Concentrate, Clem.
我们得回到医生的办公室去
We gotta get back to the offiice.
那里有个盒式录音机  不  不是那幅画!
There was a tape recorder. No, not the picture.
不是那幅画!
Not the picture.
在哪里?  这边走  来吧!
Where is it? Back here. Come on!
噢  看着我  我在那里看上很好
Oh, look at me. Hey, I look good there.
客户的档案是保密的  巴瑞斯先生
Look our files are confiidential, Mr. Barish,
我不能给你看
so I can't show you evidence.
这样说吧  克莱门汀女士
Suffiice it to say, that Miss, uh-- Miss Kruczynski
她觉得很不快乐  她想要新的生活
was not happy and she wanted to move on.
-现在告诉我关于克莱门汀的事  -所有你记得的事
Good. Now, tell me about Clementine. Just tell me everything you remember.
-他是这么说的 -我们那天看到了什么?
That's what he said. Then-- What did we see that day?
-不  等等  -嘿  快看!
No, wait. Oh, look! Hey!
-糟了!  -我们去看我祖母
Shit! We're going to see my grandma.
-乔尔  为什么  -不  我们不坐火车
Joel, why? -No, I don't want to. Joel, please! We're not going on a train.
-请不要再让我跑了  -快!
Don't make me run anymore. Come on!
米R维克医生!
Mierzwiak!
-我们总是得逃吗?  -米R维克医生!
Do we always have to run? Mierzwiak!
求求你
Please.
那么  为什么我们不从
So, why don't we begin by you telling me
你所记得的一切开始
everything you can remember.
米R维克医生!  让我醒来!
Mierzwiak! Wake me up!
对不起  巴瑞斯先生
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr. Barish.
我想你知道所有这一切的原因
I thought you understood what was going on here.
你不知道  你在消除我对她的记忆
I don't know. You're erasing her from me.
你在消除她
You're erasing me from her--
我不知道
I don't know.
你是做这事的  我知道  我现在躺在自己床上
You've got this thing. I'm in my bed. I know it.
我在我自己的回忆中
I'm in my brain.
我也是你想象的一部分  乔尔
I'm part of your imagination too,Joel.
我不能帮你什么
How can I help you from there?
我也在你的大脑里  我就是你!
Uh, I'm inside your head too. I'm you.
抱歉
Sorry..
瞧!  那是谁?
Look. Who's that?
他是我们的员工
Oh, he-he works for us.
他是帕特里克!
That's, uh, Pa-a-a-a-atrick,
宝贝男孩
baby boy.
他偷了我的身份
He's stealing my identity.
他偷了我的东西
He stole my stuff.
他用我的语言和事物去引诱我的爱人
He's seducing my girlfriend with my words and my things.
-他还偷了她的内裤
He stole her underwear.
他偷了她的内裤
我想现在就死去  克莱
I could die right now, Clem.
我真的很高兴
I'm just happy.
我从未如此感受  我现在就在自己一直想去的地方
I've never felt that before. I'm just exactly where I want to be.
我想回家了
I want to go home.
什么?
Hey. What?
克莱!
Clem!
等等  克莱!
Wait. Clem!
克莱?
Clem?
他们在清除你
They,'re erasing you.
我在这儿!
I'm here!
克莱  集中精神  他们是我雇的
Clem, focus. I hired them, okay?
对不起  我真愚蠢!
I'm so stupid.
宝贝  冷静下来  观赏美景
Sweetie, calm down. Enjoy the scenery.
在我醒来完全忘掉你之前  我得阻止他们
I need it to stop before I wake up and I don't know you anymore.
那好  直接叫他们取消手术
Okay, well, you know, just tell them to cancel it then.
你在说什么?  我做不到  我现在是睡着的
What the hell are you talking about? I can't just cancel it. I'm asleep.
那就把自己叫醒!
Wake yourself up!
那好  你想我自己醒过来  好的
Okay. You want me to wake up? Okay. Great. All right.
来试试看  我这样能不能让你高兴?
Okay, here we go. This make you happy if I try? Yeah.
我尽力试试 开始了  这真是个好主意
I'll try really hard. Here we go. That was a great idea.
这还真是有效
Boy, that's working like gangbusters.
-不要!  那让我很痒!  -我的天
Don't! That tickles me! Oh, my, goodness.
-天  那是什么?  -天 那是
Oh, my, God. What is that? Jesus Christ! What the--
是个胎记!
It's a birthmark!
这的确有用但只一会儿
It did work, for a second,
-但我动不了  -看到了?
-but I couldn't-- I couldn't move. See?
那是另一个乔尔预言吗?
Well, isn't that just another one of Joel's self-fulfilling prophecies?
用来证明我的主意是错的
It's more important to prove me wrong than to actually.
我不想谈这个  好吗?
Look, I don't want to discuss this right now, okay?
好的
Fine.
接下来怎么办?  我在听着
Then what? I'm listening.
-我也不知道  -你先清除了我
I don't know. You erased me.
所以我才会作这个清除术
That's why I'm here. That's why I'm doing this in the first place.
-对不起  -你真是!
I'm sorry. You-- You!
你了解我  我很冲动
You know me. I'm impulsive.
那就是为什么我爱你
That's what I love aboutyou.
乔尔?
Joel?
我有另一个解决问题的方法
I have anotheridea forthis problem.
现在我是你的回忆
This is a memory of me, The way
当你看到我的胯部  你就想和我在沙发上做爱
you wanted to have sex on the couch after you looked down at my crotch.
-什么?  -乔尔  那些人会找到这里
What? Joel, the eraser guys are coming here,
为什么你不把我带到其它的地方去?
so what if you take me somewhere else,
其它没有我的回忆中
somewhere where I don't belong,
我们藏在那里  直到明早
and we hide there till morning?
该死  我记不起其它没有你的地方
Oh, man. I can't remember anything without you.
那话真甜  但尽力试试  好吗?
Tsk, that's very sweet, but try, okay?
我试试
Okay.
有效了!
It's working!
我真是天才!
I'm a genius!
乔尔?
Joel?
你去哪儿呢?
Where'd you go?
我应该和你一起去的!
I'm supposed to come too!
我得去拿一个色拉盘
Listen, I'm just gonna go get a salad bowl.
你能看好汤和照顾乔尔吗?
Can you stir the soup and keep an eye on Joel?
-他喜欢在我身边  -当然
Sure. He just likes to be near me.
克莱?
Absolutely! Clem?
成功了!  天  看看这个!
It worked. My, God, look at this!
成功了!  天  看看这身衣服!
It worked! Look! Look at this dress, man!
天啊  看看!  我能带走这件衣服吗?
Oh, my God! Look at it! I wish I could take it with me.
我是谁?
Who am I?
-是哈姆林女士  -是的  哈姆林女士
Mrs. Hamlyn. Right. Mrs. Hamlyn.
这是我四岁时的回忆  啊  糟了!
I must be about four. Oh, my gosh.
找到沙拉盘了 今晚主菜是菜豆与沙拉
Found the salad bowl, so I'm serving salad and string beans.
他在那下面好吧 你怎么样?
Is he okay under there? Peanut, are you all right?
上帝  我感觉自己可以一天到晚都做家务
God, honestly, I feel like I could clean up all day.
-不介意我叫你清洗菜豆吧?
Listen, would you hate me if I asked you to clean some string beans?
-不  当然不
-No, not at all.
天  我爱死这厨房了!
Oh, my God. I love this kitchen.
-非常感谢  -她看都不看我
Thank you so much. She's not looking at me.
她很忙  她看都不看我
She's busy. She's not looking at me.
没有人愿意看我  我想要妈妈
No one ever looks at me. I want my mommy.
乔伊宝贝. 嘿,乔伊!乔伊!
Oh, baby, Joel. Hey, Joely! Joely,!
-他在下面还好吗? -嗯 还好
Is every Iittle peanut under there okay? Mm-hmm! He's fine.
你有什么可喝吗?
Do you have something to drink?
想喝杯鸡尾酒吗?  现在还没到五点
Would you drink a cocktail at this hour? I mean, I know it's not 5:00.
-有伏特加酒就好了  -等等  我去看看有没有
I would die for a vodka. Oh, hang on. Let me check if I have that.
好的  我在这儿等  乔尔
Okay! I'm just gonna wait right here. Joel!
呃，乔伊
Uh,Joely.
-你妈妈要我照看你  回到桌下去 -我要冰淇淋
Your mother wants me to mind you. Get back underthe table. Ice cream.
-冰淇淋  -不  那要到你吃完饭后
Ice cream. No, not until after you know you've had your dinner.
乔尔  来吧!
Come on, Joel!
乔尔  快长大!
Joel, grow up!
不要离开我  克莱
Don't leave me, Clem. Oh, my God, Clem.
这有点不对劲  我害怕
This is sort of warped. I'm scared.
-我要妈妈  -不要哭  乔尔宝贝
I want my mommy! Don't cry, baby Joel.
乔尔宝贝  没事的  乔尔
Baby Joel, it's okay. Joel.
乔尔!  别哭了!  看着我!  我想这有效果了
Stop it! Look, I think it's working. Look, we're hidden, Joel.
宝贝  看着
Hey, honey, look.
待着别动
Wait there.
我的胯部还在  就像你回忆中的一样
My crotch is still here just as you remembered it.
讨厌!
Yuck.
停了
It stopped.
-什么?  -清除停止了
What? It stopped erasing.
这太糟了!
This is terrible.
他到映像外面去了
He's offthe map. He's off the map.
-他去哪儿呢? -不知道
Where? I don't know where!
你是什么意思 我不知道他到哪儿去了!
What do you mean? I don't know where!
这很糟 太糟了! 我眼镜在哪儿?
This is bad. This is very, very bad news. Where are my glasses?
好了 糟糕
Okay. Crap.
我们该怎么办? 我该怎么办?
Okay. What do we do? What do I do?
-我们该做些什么? -不知道 不知道
What shall we do? I don't know what to do. I don't know what to do.
-我们该做些什么? -我不知道 别说了 好吗?
- What shall we do? - Crap. Crap. I don't know!
-我说了我不知道 -对不起 我们该做些什么?
- I just said that I don't know what to do. - I'm sorry. What do we do?
我不知道 你在烦我 放松些
I don't know. Now, look,you're freaking me out. Mellow out.
但你必须得做点什么 他不能半途中醒来
Well, you have to do something. He could wake up all half-baked.
安静 你快把我逼疯了
Quiet. You're freaking me out. Shh. Shh.
全部黏糊糊的而且只烤到一半，嗯，那听起来真酷!
All gooey and-- and half-baked. Hmm, that sounds so good.
-糟糕! -我饿了
Oh, shit! I'm hungry.
糟糕!
Oh, shit. Oh! Oh!
什么? 什么? 什么?
What? Oh! What, what? What?
-我们应该把医生叫过来 -不 不要
- We should call Howard. - No way. No, sir, man.
这是我的工作 我能处理
This is my-- I can handle this.
-我们不能麻烦他 -他的手术只作了一半
I can't call Howard. He's an unbaked cookie.
没时间胡闹了
He's-- There's no time to fuck around.
-一切都在我的控制之中  -不要瞎说了
I got this under control. What Are you talking about?
-不要胡闹了  -好吧  我打电话给他
Stop fucking around! Okay, I'll call Howard.
-喂  是霍华德吗?  我是斯坦
Hello, Howard? Hey, it's Stan.
我正在做手术的这个人
I'm working on this guy down here
我们在一段时间内没有他的信号了
and we seem to have lost him for a moment,
而且我无法找到他
and, uh, I can't-- I can't bring him back up.
告诉我在信号消失前发生了什么
Okay, tell me what happened before he disappeared.
我不太肯定  我离开了一会
Well, I wasn't sure, really, cause I was away from the monitor for a minute.
那段时间用的是自动程序
and I had it on autopilot because I had to,
我得上厕所
I had to pee.
-帕特里克在哪儿?  -帕特里克生病回家了
Where's Patrick? Patrick? Patrick had to go home sick.
-好的  告诉我地址  -真对不起
Okay, what's the address? I know. I'm so sorry.
-快说吧  -南村街159号
That's okay. Come on. I'm at 159 South Village.
-好的  -公寓单元1E  洛克威尔中心
Yeah. Apartment 1E. Rockville Center.
-玛丽  他马上就到  -什么?
Mary? He's coming right now. Yeah?
我会留下来
I'm staying.
-收拾好你的东西  玛丽  -我要留下
-Get your stuff, Mary. -I'm staying.
-我想你应该离开  -不要
I thinkyou should go. Hell, no.
玛丽  真糟糕!
Mary-- Shit.
-我烂醉了  -不要  玛丽
I am so stoned. Please, Mary.
-你得离开  -我得醒酒  玛丽
You have to go. Stop being stoned, Mary.
我不想他看到我醉酒的样子
I don't want him to see me stoned.
-玛丽  你知不知道我们会有什么样的麻烦
Mary. you have no idea how much trouble we're gonna get into
-我看上去真糟!
if Howard comes. I look like shit!
乔伊 不要! 乔尔 看!
Joely, stop it! Joel! Look! Hey, Joel!
-乔尔!  -我想她来看我
Joel! I want her to pick me up.
-奇怪 那欲望是这么的强烈 -乔尔 看着我 看着我!
It's weird how strong that desire is. Joel, look at me! Look.
早上醒来时你还会记得我
You'll remember me in the morning,
你来找我把我们的事告诉我  我们重新开始
and you'll come to me and you'll tell me about us, and we'll start over.
帕特?  我刚帕特?
Pat? I just-- Pat?
我想我们可以来点鸡尾酒
I thought we could have a little cocktail.
那个叫帕特里克的家伙  他在模仿我
That Patrick guy-- he's copying me.
帕特里克?
What Patrick guy?
-那个家伙!  -什么?
That guy! What?
他在我的家里
He's here in my apartment.
他也是做清除术的人
He's one of those eraser guys.
他在为你做手术时爱上了你
He fell for you when they were doing you,
现在他向你介绍自己  好像他从来不认识你
and now he's introduced himself like he doesn't even know you,
现在你们在约会
and you guys are dating.
真的吗?  他可爱吗?
Really? Is he cute?
克莱  你没事的
Clem, there's nothing wrong with you.
你是我遇到过的最好的人
You're the most wonderful person I've ever met.
你你很善良
You-- You're kind,
美丽
beautiful
聪明、幽默
and smart and funny
而且人好
and nice.
什么?
What?
好了
Okay. All right.
Okay. Oh!
-快点 快点 来吧 -小心些
Move, move, move! Come on. Let's go. Careful, careful.
好的
Fine.
天  我还醉着
Oh, my God. I'm still stoned.
你给我的眼药水屁用没有
Those eyedrops you gave me didn't do shit.
冷静  冷静
Be cool. Cool.
-玛丽 你怎么在这里? -嗯 霍华德
Hello, Mary. What are you doing here? Oh, hi, Howard.
她只是过来帮忙
She was just here to help out.
我想尽力理解整个过程
I wanted to understand as much as I could about the procedure as possible.
我想这对我的工作很重要
I think it's important for my job to understand the inner workings
理解这工作中的细节
of the work that we do.
这工作不是我做的
Well, not that I do, but the work that is done
而是与我共事的人所作的
by people where I also work, the work of my colleagues.
好了  让我们来看看
All right, well, let's see If we can,
怎样解决吧
get to the bottom of this, shall we?
好的
Uh, yeah.
-这很奇怪  -我已试过了
Well, that's odd. I already tried that.
-你试过C门了吗?  -当然试过了
Did you try going through the C-gate? Yeah, of course.
我的意思是是的
I mean yes.
好的
Yeah.
那么
All right.
-你想连上去么?  -是的
You want to get linked up? Yeah.
好的
All right.
我已经使用了检查程序
I already-- I ran the utility programs,
但并没找到什么
and I had nothing there,
所以我根据打印日志检查了所有的记忆扫描
so I checked all the memories against the printed logs.
霍华德
Here, Howard. Okay.
-请坐  -谢谢你
I got you a chair. There you go. Oh, Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome. Whew!
好的  我会检查他所有的记忆
All right, I'm gonna-- I'm gonna go through the entire memory,
看看是怎么回事
see if something comes up.
我亲爱的 我亲爱的克莱门汀
Oh my darling, oh my darling,Oh my darling Clementine
我喜欢在水槽里洗澡
I love being bathed in the sink.
这感觉是多么的安全
Such a feeling of security.
我从来没见你这么高兴  乔尔宝贝
I've never seen you happier, baby Joel.
在这儿
There it is.
我不能理解他怎么会跑到映像之外?
I don't understand why it's off the map like that.
他到底在那里干什么?
What the heck was he doing there?
他的眼晴睁开了
His eyes are open.
-以前睁开过吗?  -没有
-Has this happened before with him?  -No.
这不太妙
Oh, this is-- this is not good. No.
我不得不
I'm gonna have to--
给他注射这个
I'm gonna have to give him this.
难道你不知道吗?  我爱你
Can't you see I love you, Antoine?
好的  正常了
Okay, we're back in.
干得真漂亮  霍华德
That was beautiful to watch, Howard.
就像外科手术或音乐会的钢琴师
Like a surgeon or a concert pianist or something.
谢谢  玛丽
Thank you, Mary.
霍华德  你该去睡睡  我想我能处理了
Howard, you should get some sleep. I think I'll be fine now.
但难道你不知道吗?  我爱你  安托万
Why can't you see I love you, Antoine?
我真幸运
Lucky me.
来亲我吧
Lay one on me.
别叫我安托万
Don't call me Antoine.
-我的名字是娃利  -我知道
My name is Wally. Yes, I know,
但如果男人的名字叫娃利  哪个女人会爱呢?
but how can a woman love a man with a name like Wally?
那是什么?
Oh! Oh! What was that?
天啊  有人从你的屁股后冒出来
Hey. My God, there's people coming out of your butt.
是吗?
There is?
-找到了  -橘柑!
- Got it. - Tangerine!
-乔尔  你在干什么?  -我们得赶快走!
What, Joel-- What are you doing? We gotta go.
请快走  快走!
Go on. Please, please go. Please go!
你可以跑  但你躲藏不了
You can run but you can't hide.
克莱  快跑!
Clem, come on!
到了
There I am.
那卡车!
That truck.
医生  求求你
Doc? Please.
好吧  让我们从你所
All right, let's begin by you telling me
记得的所有事开始
everything you remember--
这真奇怪  他还有已经清除掉了的记忆
That's strange. He's in a memory that we've already erased.
好吧 至少我们知道他在那里 可以追踪他了 对吧?
Oh, well, at least we know where he is. He's back on track, right?
来吧  克莱
Come on, Clem.
看起来他好像在反抗这个过程
He seems to have developed some sort of resistance to the procedure.
-我不想再跑了  -糟了!
I don't want to run any,more. Shit.
来吧 把我藏到更深的地方去 埋藏起来
Come on, come on. Hide me somewhere deeper, somewhere really buried.
-哪儿?  -把我藏到你的糗事中
Where? Hide me in your humiliation.
-糗事中?  -来吧  你这个胆小鬼!
Humiliation. Come on,you bigbaby,!
对不起  好吗?
I'm sorry. okay?
让我送你回去
Let me drive you home.
-再见 霍华德 -等等! 霍华德!
- Bye, Howard. - No, wait. Howard.
他又消失了
He's disappeared again.
-天哪!  -对不起  霍华德
Oh, dear. I'm so sorry. Howard.
糗事
Humiliation.
乔尔
Hu-mi-lia-- Joel.
我也不喜欢
I don't like it either.
我在尽力找到恐怖的秘密之地
I'm just trying to find horrible secret places to--
乔尔  我有一个惊喜
Joel, honey, I have a surprise-- I just--
宝贝  是什么  我明早再问你
you know what, honey? I'm just gonna ask you in the morning.
晚安  甜心
Good night, sweetheart.
-对不起  乔尔  -别说啦!
I'm sorry,Joel. Joely. Shut up.
快看!  乔尔!
Look! Joel!
-乔尔  快看!  -什么?
Joel, look! What?
看看我们在什么地方
Look where we are!
噢  不!
Whoo!
克莱  这不好
Clem, this isn't good.
那把我藏到更深的地方去
Then hide me somewhere-- somewhere really, buried.
-杀它! 杀它! -我不能! 我要回家
Hit it! Hit it! I can't! I gotta go home.
我以后再作!
I'll do it later!
来吧  你这个胆小鬼!
Come on, you big sissy!
快看啦  他有女朋友!
Ooh, he has a girlfiriend!
等等 我到底在干什么? 你知道吗? 佛雷德
Wait. What am I doing? You know something, Freddy? And he loves her!
我再也不怕你了
You don't scare me anymore.
乔尔
Joel!
-乔伊 起来 走吧 这不值得 -打他! 打他!
Joely, get up. Come on, it's not worth it. Hit him! Hit him!
这不值得 乔尔!  他没在听!
They're not worth it,Joel! He's not listening!
-走吧  乔尔!  -蠢货!
Come on,Joel. Stupid!
-真丢脸!  -没事啦
I'm so ashamed. It's okay.
-你现在是小孩子  -是的
You were a little kid. Yeah?
-来吧  -这是我以前的家
Come on. That's where I live-- lived.
我希望我还是孩子时就认识你
I wish I knew you when I was a kid.
你喜欢我的粉红帽子吗?  来  让你感觉好些
Do you like my pink hat? Here, look feel better.
这次你可以真的杀掉我  来吧
You can really kill me this time.
-轮到我了? 来吧 1 2 3 -你真的会死掉吗?
It's my turn? Go. One, two, three. You're really gonna die though.
好吧 1 2 3
Okay. One, two, three.
死吧!
You're dead.
那是我妈  没事的  我们在开玩笑
Oh, my mom. It's-- It's okay. We're playing.
-你好 乔尔的妈妈 他在杀害我 -这不是真的
Hi, Joel's mom. He's killing me. It's not real.
克莱 你死了吗?
Clem, are you dead yet?
你死了!
You're dead!
我开始清楚情况了
I think I got the hang of this.
可我仍然无法理解  但我会很快找到他
I still don't understand it, but I 'm finding him quickly enough.
克莱!
Clem!
乔伊?
Jo--Joely?
你还好吧  乔尔?
Are you okay, Joel?
乔尔?  乔尔?
Joel? Joel?
天啊  那真可怕
Oh, my God. That was terrible.
那像三秒钟
Okay, okay. That was like three seconds.
再来一次  我得走了
All right. Let me do it one more time. One more, then I get to go.
好的
Okay.
-看那个  -真酷
Look at this. This is so cool!
小心  小心!
Cool. Look out! Look out!
该死!  雪球散了
Shit! It's fluff.
我们的小屋!
Our house!
来吧
Come on. Whoo-hoo! Come on.
-来吧  -我们得快跑
Come on. We gotta go!
来吧
Come on!
克莱  我们得快跑
We gotta go. Clem?
得快跑
We gotta go.
来吧
Aah! Come on!
我们现在没有时间玩!
No! This is a really bad time for this!
放开我! 哦,上帝!
Get off me! Oh, God!
-我们甚至不知道要去哪儿  -会好的
I don't even know where we're going. It's gonna be fun. Come on.
-这就是最好的地方 -不 这边走
It's the best place. No, this way. No, this way.
不 不 这边走 你在拖后腿
No, no. This way. You're no help at all.
你是怎么啦?
What's wrong with you?
放开我  乔尔!
Let go of me,Joel!
霍华德  我喜欢看你工作
I like watching you work, Howard.
我想
I guess, uh--
出去呼吸新鲜空气
I guess I'll go out for-- for some air,
如果没人介意的话
if nobody minds.
看来这里的一切都在控制之中了
It looks like you have everything under control here.
是的
Yeah, that's, uh--
好吧
that's fine.
你喜欢名言吗  霍华德?
Do you like quotes, Howard?
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
你知道的  像闻名的名言
Oh,you know like famous quotes?
我发现读这些很有灵感
I find reading them inspirational,
我偶然读到一些  你可能也会喜欢
and in my reading, I've come across some I thought you might like too.
那好  说来听听
Oh, well, I-- I'd love to hear some.
这里有一句说
There's one that goes,
祝福那些健忘的人吧 因为他们战胜了自己过去的错误
Blessed are the forgetful for they get the better even of their blunders.
-是尼采说的 对吧? -对
That's Nietzsche, right? Yeah.
-我以为我可以说句你不知道 -噢 不
And here I thought I could tell you something you didn't know. Oh, no.
这是一句很好的名言 我很高兴我俩都知道
It's-- It's a good quote. I'm happy we both know it.
这里还有一首我喜欢的
Yeah. Oh, and there's this other one I like.
教皇亚历山大的诗
It's by Pope Alexander, and it goes--
-是亚历山大・蒲柏吧?  -噢 是的
Alexander Pope? Oh, yeah.
我一直告诫自己不要说成了教皇亚历山大
It's just that I told myself I not to say Pope Alexander and
但我还是这样说了 像个傻瓜
sound like a dope and then I go ahead and say it.
-这没什么大不了的  -你真是甜心
It's no big deal. You're such a sweetheart.
这句名言说 "贞洁女性的命运是多么幸福"
The quote goes, "How happy, is the blameless vestal's lot?
忘记世界  被世界遗忘
The world forgetting by the world forgot.
美丽心灵的永恒阳光
Eternal sunshine of the spotless mind.
实现每一个祷告  拒绝每一个愿望
Each prayer accepted and each wish resigned.
我想当一头巨大的大象
I want to be a great big, huge elephant
带着像那样的大喇叭.
with a huge trunk like that.
克莱?  克莱门汀?
Clem? Clementine?
我没听过这句  真美
I haven't heard that one. It's lovely.
我想也许这句合你心意
I just thought it would be appropriate maybe.
我真的欣赏你所做的工作
I really admire the work you do, Howard.
-我也不想变得这么亲密  -这很好 我
I don't mean to be so familiar. Oh, it's fine. It's fine.
我很高兴能听
I'm happy to hear--
对不起
I'm sorry.
我爱上你已经很久了
I've loved you for a very long time.
-我不该这样说  -玛丽 不
I shouldn't have said that. Oh, Mary. no.
你是一个很好的女孩
It's-- You're a wonderful girl.
但我有妻子和小孩  你知道的
But I-- You know, I have a wife and kids.
我有妻子和小孩
You know I have a wife and kids.
哦  玛丽
Oh, Mary
玛丽  我们不能这样
Oh, Mary, we can't do this.
你早  米R维克夫人
Well, good morning, Mrs. Mierzwiak.
-怎么啦?  -我的天啊!
What? Oh, my God!
她是谁?
Who is it?
谢谢你  斯坦  真是多谢!
Thank you, Stan. Thanks a lot.
霍丽斯!
Hollis!
等等  霍丽斯
Wait. Wait, wait, wait. Hollis.
-我就知道  霍华德  -霍丽斯  我们不必这样
- I knew it, Howard. - Hollis, it didn't start out to be like this.
我是来工作的  霍丽斯  下次我不再犯了!
I came here to work. Hollis, this is a one-time mistake!
我是一个突然发傻的蠢女孩
I'm a stupid girl with a stupid crush! Yeah.
我发誓是我引诱他的
I swear I basically forced him into it!
不要这么坏  霍华德  告诉这女孩
Don't be a monster, Howard. Tell the girl.
告诉我什么?
Tell me what?
可怜的孩子
Oh, you poor kid.
你可以拥有他
You can have him.
你已经拥有过了
You did.
她说什么?
What?
我们以前已经爱过了
we have a history.
抱歉  当时是你想要作清除术
I'm sorry. Y-You wanted the procedure.
你
You--
你当时想要清除掉记忆
You wanted it done
那么你就可以克服
so you could get past,
我还得去完成工作
I have to, uh, finish the work in there.
天快亮了
It's almost morning.
我们以后再谈
We'll talk later.
好吗?
Okay?
让我送你回家吧
Let me give you a lift home.
该死  怎么回事?
Fuck this thing. Damn it.
-你好  -你好
Hi. Hi.
我没想到你还会来见我
Didn't figure you'd show your face around me again.
我猜你感到羞耻
I guess I thought you were humiliated.
毕竟你逃跑了
You did run away after all.
我只是想看看你
I just needed to see you.
什么?
Yeah?
我想
I'd like to,
带你出去逛逛或干点什么
take you out or something.
你已结婚了
You're married.
还没  我没结婚
Not yet. Not married.
不  我没结婚
No, I'm not married, no.
瞧 伙计 我现在就告诉你 我的要求很高
Look, man, I'm telling you right off the bat I'm high maintenance,
我不会做你的情妇
so I'm not gonna tiptoe around your marriage
或什么第三者
or whatever it is you've got going there.
如果你想作我的恋人  就只能是我一个
if you wanna be with me, you're with me.
好的
Okay.
很多男孩认为我是一个完美的概念
Too many guys think I'm a concept or I complete them,
我使他们感到完整或真正的活着
or I'm gonna make them alive.
但我只是一个寻找内心宁静的混乱女孩
But I'm just a fucked-up girl who's looking for my own peace of mind.
-别把你的想法强加给我  -我很清楚的记得这话
Don't assign me yours. I remember that speech really well.
-我让你记住我了吧?  -你让全人类都记住你了
I had you pegged didn't I? You had the whole human race pegged.
也许吧
Hmm. Probably.
我仍然认为你会回来拯救我的一生
I still thought you were gonna save my life,
即便我们都忘记了彼此
even after that.
我知道的
I know.
一切都会不同的
It would be different
如果我们能再有一个机会
If we could just give it another go around.
记住我
Remember me.
尽你的最大努力
Try your best.
也许我们能够做到
Maybe we can.
好了  告诉我你还记得些什么
Okay, so just tell me what you remember,
我们会把它清除掉
and, uh, then we'll take it from there.
好的
Okay.
我对你一见钟情
I liked you immediately.
但你却不解风情
You didn't come on to me at all.
我喜欢那样
I liked that.
起初 在你身边我连话都说不出来
I was so tongue-tied around you at first.
我只是想让你觉得我很聪明
I wanted you to think I was smart.
我迫不及待想和你工作
I couldn't wait to come to work.
我幻想我们结婚
I had these fantasies of us being married
抚养小孩 只是
and having kids and just--
哦  我不能这么做
Oh, I can't do this.
我们都同意这样做是最好的  玛丽
We agreed it's forthe best, Mary..
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
天啊!
Oh, God.
-我来拿底部  -不 不
I'll take the bottom and you-- No, no, no. Here.
-我搬得动  -你想我拿那个吗?
I can take that. So you want me to carry that?
-帮我一把  -亲爱的  你能拿螺旋桨吗?
Help me with that. Can you get the cooler? Honey, the cooler is--
-那很轻 - 让我来搬
That's light, huh? Oh, I can get that. You can get it.
不 不
No, no, no, no!
-不要动任何东西  -我可以拿那飞机
Don't take anything. I can take the plane.
把东西收拾好  关上车门
Put the thing up. Put the gate back up.
这是我们初遇的那天
This is the day,we met.
你站在海浪前  我就在远方画着你
You were down by the surf. I could just make you out in the distance.
我记得就在那时  我被深深吸引住
I remember being drawn to you even then.
我想 哈 奇怪 我在画别人的背
I thought, "Wow, how odd. I'm drawn to someone's back. "
那件让我牢牢记住的运动衫
You were in that orange sweatshirt that I would come to know so well.
充满爱恨交织
and even hate, eventually.
当时我想  太酷了  橙黄色的运动衫
At the time I thought, " How cool! An orange sweatshirt."
你好
Hi there.
我刚才看见你
I saw you sitting over here
独自坐在这儿
by yourself,
于是我想  感谢上帝
and I thought, "Thank God.
原来还有不会玩这些东西的正常人
Someone normal who doesn't know how to interact at these things either."
是啊
Yeah.
我不知该说些什么
I don't ever know what to say.
我是克莱门汀
I'm Clementine.
我能吃块你的鸡肉吗?
Can I borrow a piece of your chicken?
你就直接拿了
And then you just took it
连我的回答都不等
without waiting for an answer.
如此亲密
It was so intimate,
就像我们已经是恋人
Iike we were already lovers.
我叫乔尔
I'm Joel.
你好 乔尔
Hi,Joel.
好了 不准取笑我的名字
So, no jokes about my name.
你的意思是像  "我亲爱的 我亲爱的克莱门汀"
You mean like Oh my darling, oh my darling, my darling Clementine
腰浆果狗?  就像那种笑话?
Huckleberry Hound, that sort of thing?
对  就像那样
Yeah. Like that.
不会  我不会开你玩笑的
Oh, no jokes. No jokes.
当我还是小孩时  我最爱看的卡通就是腰浆果狗
One of my favorite things when I was a kid was my Huckleberry Hound doll.
我想你的名字就像魔法
I think your name is magical.
时候到了  乔尔
This is it, Joel.
很快我就会彻底消失
It's gonna be gone soon.
我知道
I know.
我们该怎么办?
What dowe do?
好好享受这段时光
Enjoy it.
-你结过婚吗?  -没有
You married? No.
我们去拜访下邻居
Let's move into this neighborhood!
我的确和一个人生活在一起
I do sort of live with someone though.
-男的女的?  -什么?
Male or female? What?
女的女的
Female. Female.
那至少我没选错人
At least I'm not barking up the wrong tree.
-你认识这些人?  -当然不认识  来吧
You know these people? No, of course not. Come on.
他们可能养了狗
They might have a dog.
没有狗
There's no dog.
你在干什么?
What Are you doing?
-外面很冷  -我不敢相信
It's freezing out. I can't believe this.
克莱门汀!
-Clementine! - There we go.
进来吧 不会有事的
Come on, man. The water's fine.
今晚没人会来这儿 相信我
Nobody's coming here tonight. Believe me.
真黑
It's dark.
你女朋友叫什么名字?
So, what's your girlfriend's name?
内奥米 但我们真的没有
Naomi, but we're not really-- I mean--
我们
We're-- Whatever.
这里真好  现在我去找蜡烛  火柴
So this is great. Now I can look for, candles, matches
和酒柜
and the liquor cabinet.
天!
Oh, God.
我想我们该走了
I think we should go.
-电话不通  -什么?
There's no phone line. What?
-我们该走了  -为什么?
I think we should go. Why?
今晚这就是我们的房子
It's our house just for tonight.
我们是"大卫和鲁思・拉什金"
We are "David and Ruth Laskin."
你想当谁?
Which one do you want to be?
我想当鲁思  但我当其他的也行
I prefer to be Ruth, but I can be flexible.
拜托
What are you do--
-美酒!  -天
Alcohol! Oh, boy.
你喝酒吗?
So, Are you okay with wine?
-我不知道  -你来选酒
I don't know. Well, you choose the wine.
我去找卧室  去找更多鲁思的东西
I'm gonna go find the bedroom and slip into something more Ruth.
-我此时很凶残  -我真的该走了
I'm Ruth-less at the moment. I really should go.
我得赶去坐车
I've gotta catch my ride.
那走吧!
So go.
我走了
I did.
我想你也许是个疯子
I thought maybe you were a nut,
但你只是兴奋
but you were exciting.
我希望你留下
I wish you'd stayed.
我也希望我留下  现在我希望我留下
I wish I'd stayed too. Now I wish I'd stayed.
我希望自己做过很多事
I wish I'd done a lot of things.
上帝  我希望
Oh, God, I wish I had--
我真的希望我能留下
I wish I'd stayed. I do.
-当我下楼来时  你已经走了
Well, I came back down stairs and you were gone.
-我出去了  我从门口出去了
-I walked out. I walked out the door.
-为什么?  -我不知道  我像个吓坏的小孩一样
Why? I don't know. I felt like a scared little kid.
我就像  我想不出来  我不知道
I was like-- It was above my head. I don't know.
你吓坏了?
You were scared?
是的
Yeah.
我想你了解我那一点
Thought you knew that about me.
我想我跑到篝火那里  逃避我的羞辱
I ran back to the bonfiire trying to outrun my humiliation, I think.
-是我说错了什么吗?  -是的
Was it something I said? Yeah.
你说 "那走吧"
You said, "So go"
用那样轻蔑的口气  你知道吗?
with such disdain, you know?
-对不起  -没什么
Oh, I'm sorry. It's okay.
乔伊?
Joely?
如果你这次留下来会怎么样?
What if you stayed this time?
我已走出了门
I walked out the door.
没有记忆留下了
There's no memory left.
那至少回来告别
Come back and make up a good-bye, at least.
假装至少我们告别过
Let's pretend we had one.
别了 乔尔
Bye, Joel.
我爱你
I love you.
到蒙塔克来找我
Meet me in Montauk.
飞机坠毁了  不是我让它坠毁的
I didn't crash the plane. The plane crashed. I didn't crash the plane.
是你用遥控器把飞机坠毁的
You were operating the plane with the remote control and then it crashed.
风太大了
It was fucking windy. Come on, man.
你晕晕的还硬要开车
You're stoned, and you're driving.
是的  白粉使我平衡  白粉使我兴奋
Yeah, the pot balances it out. The pot brings you back up.
所以我想喝酒时就会去吸它
That's why I smoke it. If I'm going to be drinking then I'll smoke it.
的确有效  在科学网络上
It does. That's a medical fiact.
这是被医学证实了的
It was proven on the Science Network.
-宝贝  看好路  -我什么也看不见
Honey, just watch the road. I can't see shit.
我看见你和一个漂亮的女性谈话
I saw you talking to somebody pretty.
-她人很好  -是的  那是谁?
She was nice. Yeah, man. Who was that?
她只是一个女孩
She was, um, just a girl.
完了
Okay.
那我把卡车开回去
So I gotta-- I gotta drop the van off.
谢谢  斯坦  谢谢
Thanks, Stan. Thanks.
我们以后再谈
We'll talk.
-你拿走了很多你的东西  -是的  我的东西
You got a lot of your stuff there, I see. Yeah, that's right. My stuff.
我知道你不会再回来  要是我也会这么做
I take it you're not coming back. I wouldn't come back if l was you either.
-你敢发誓你不知道么?  -我发誓
Do you swear you didn't know? I swear.
-是你给我做的记忆清除吗?  -不是  上帝作证
So you didn't do the erasing? Of course not. God, no.
难道你没怀疑过我和他曾是一对?
And you never even suspected we were together?
也许有一次
Once, maybe.
我工作回来  你在车里
I was coming back from a job and you were at his car.
我看见你俩在交谈
I saw you two talking.
我向你招手  你冲我笑
So I waved to you, and you giggled, you know.
我看上去怎样?
How'd I look?
看上去很高兴
You looked happy.
高兴有着自己的秘密
Happy with a secret.
以后呢?
And after that?
我再也没有看见你俩像那样了  所以我想
I never saw you two together again like that, so I just--
那也许只是自己的想象
I don't know. I just figured I was imagining things.
我真的喜欢你 玛丽・斯皮尔
I really like you, Mary Svevo.
你知道吗?
You know that?
谢谢
Thanks.
让我先去刷牙
Let me get my toothbrush.
你在哪儿  克莱? 我很担心.
Where are you, Clem? I'm worried.
我感觉你对我火气很大  我不知道自己做了什么
I feel like you're mad at me and I don't know what I did.
我做了什么?
What did I do?
我是如此的爱你
I love you so much.
我愿意做任何让你高兴的事
I'll do anything to make you happy.
告诉我你想我干什么  我就去干什么
Tell me what you want me to do and I'll do it.
听着  今早我会来看你是否还好
Listen, I'm gonna stop by this morning just to make sure you're okay.
开车吧  司机
Vamonos, senor.
昨晚我过得真棒!
I had a really nice time last night.
真棒?
Nice?
我一生中过得最棒的一夜是
I had the best fucking night of my entire fucking life
昨晚
Last night.
很好
That's better.
-这真怪  -致所有霍华德医生的病人们
This is weird. To all patients of Dr.Howard Mierzwiak.
我叫玛丽・斯皮尔 你们见过我 但你们已不记得我了
My name is Mary Svevo. We've met, but you don't remember me.
我为一间你们雇来消除  你们部分回忆的公司工作
I worked for a company you hired to have part of your memory erased."
当我发现这很可怕后
I have since decided that this is a horrible.
为了补偿  我把档案寄还给每一个人
In order to correct this, I'm sending everyone's fiile back to them.
我是克莱门汀・克罗斯基
My name is Clementine Kruczynski.
我来清除对乔尔・巴瑞斯的回忆
I'm here to erase Joel Barish.
-这是什么?  -我不知道
What is this? I don't know.
他很无聊 这理由足够清除对他的回忆吗?
He's boring. Is that enough reason to erase someone?
我最近在想  以前的我和现在的我差异太大
I've been thinking lately, how I was before and how I am now,
他改变了我
and it's like he changed me.
现在我总是很生气
I feel like I'm alway's pissy, now.
和他在一起时  我不再像是我自己
I don't like myself when I'm with him. I don't like myself anymore.
我甚至不能忍受看见他  那悲惨  懦弱的笑容
I can't stand to even look at him. That pathetic wimpy apologetic smile.
-那真是个令人讨厌的家伙 知道吗?
-That sort of wounded puppy shit he does, you know?
-你在干什么?
-What are you doing?
-我什么也没干
I 'm not doing anything.
-我和他之间的爱情玫瑰已凋谢了
-The bloom is certainly fucking off i the rose at this point.
-你在耍我吗?  -没有!
-Are you screwing with me? -No!
-你在耍我!  -乔尔  我没有
-You are screwing with me. -Joel, I'm not!
-你显然是  -瞧  让我们
-You clearly are. -Look, let's just take a minute and--
帕特里克  滚开!
Patrick, get the fuck away.
-甜心  -他妈的滚!
Oh, sweetheart-- Get the fuck away from me!
-我们能谈谈吗?  -不  滚!
Can we talk about it? No! Get the fuck away!
乔尔・巴瑞斯
Joel Barish.
你好  克莱门汀
Hey, Clementine. Hey.
见到你真好
Nice to see you. Yeah.
真的没受过多少教育
Really, very. educated.
我的意思是  她很聪明  但没受过多少教育
I mean, she's smart, I think, but not educated.
我没办法和她谈论书籍  你知道吗?
I couldn't really talk to her about books, you know?
她只是个喜欢看杂志的女孩
She's more of a magazine-reading girl.
她的用词发音很差
Her vocabulary. Leaves something to be desired.
有时令我在公共场所感到难堪
Sometimes-- I was embarrassed in public
-你好  -因为她会把
Hi. because she would pronounce
-图书馆都读错
Library. "libary.. " Hi.
看我找到了什么
Look what I found.
我想克莱门汀真正吸引人的地方
I think ifithere's a truly seductive quality about Clementine,
就是她的个性能让你忘却世俗烦恼
it's that her personality promises to take you out of the mundane.
你把我画得皮包骨
You made me look skinny.
她就像燃烧的流星
Amazing, burning meteorite
载着你去极乐之地
will carry you to another world where things are exciting.
但你很快就会发现
But what you quickly learn is that
那只不过是精心设计的圈套
it's really an elaborate ruse.
对不起冲你大喊大叫
I'm sorry yelled at you.
-没什么  -一种显而易见、华而不实的圈套
It's okay. So flashy, in a kind of obvious way.
-但那仍然诱惑着你  -乔尔  我真的喜欢你
But still, it seduces you. Joel, I really like you.
我恨自己说了你的坏话
I hate that I said mean things about you.
-我关掉录音机  好吗?  -等等  这很公平
-Let me turn this off, okay? - Hey, it's-- it's only fiair.
真实的克莱门汀在哪里?
Where's the real Clementine?
她发型能有什么狗屁意义?  简直是扯蛋!
I mean the whole thing with the hair-- it's all bullshit.
-我真的喜欢你的发型  -谢谢你
- I really like your hair. -Thank you.
-真的喜欢  -谢谢你
I really like your hair. Thank you.
-我真的  -整个世界都混乱了
I do. The world's a goddamn mess.
-她想靠改变头发颜色突出反叛个性吗?
Is it some kind of a revolt? Change your hair color.
-你想喝点什么?
-You want a drink or something?
有威士忌吗?
Do you have any whiskey?
不  我不认为她的性生活是有目的的
No, I don't think her sex is motivated.
昨晚我们在一起时  我看得很清楚
I saw it clearly the last night we were together.
那不是性生活  那是悲哀!
It wasn't sex. It was just sad.
对不起  我以为威士忌还有很多
Hey. Sorry. I thought there was more.
克莱认为让人们喜欢她的唯一方法就是
The only way Clem thinks she can get people to like her
和他们上床
is to fuck
或至少给出这个可能
or at least dangle the possibility of getting fucked in front of them.
她是如此的绝望和没有安全感
And she's so desperate and insecure
迟早她会和所有人上床
that she'll sooner or later go around fucking everybody.
-我不是那样  -我不会那样想你
I don't do that. I wouldn't think that about you.
-因为我不是  -我知道
-Because I don't. -I know.
但你那样说真的很伤我心  因为我不是那样的人
Because it really hurts me that you said that because I don't do that.
-很对不起  -对不起  我得走了
I'm so sorry. I 'm sorry about all this. I 'm gonna go.
我感到迷惑  我想我真的不能在这里待下去
I'm a little confused. I don't really think I can be here.
-别了  -我以为自己很了解她
Bye. I thought I knew her so well.
-能认识你真好  -但我根本就不了解她
It was nice meeting you and all. But I don't know her at all.
经过了这么长的时间
What a loss to spend that much time with someone,
才发现她是最熟悉的陌生人
only to fiind out that she's a stranger.
等等!
Wait.
-什么?  -我不知道
What? I don't know.
-你想要怎样  乔尔? 就等一会儿!
Just wait. Just wait. What do you want, Joel?
我不知道  我只想你再等等
I don't know. I want you to wait for just a while.
-好的  -真的?
Okay. Really?
我不是一个完美的概念  乔尔
I'm not a concept, Joel.
我只是一个寻找内心宁静的混乱女孩
I'm just a fucked-up girl who's looking for my own peace of i mind.
-我并不完美  -我找不到不去爱你的理由
-I'm not perfect. -I can't see anything that I don't like about you.
-我找不到  -但你会的
Right now I can't. But you will. But you will.
你知道  你会找到的
You know, you will think of things,
而我会对你感到厌倦  觉得拘束
and I'll get bored with you and feel trapped
因为这以前就发生过
because that's what happens with me.
好吧
Okay.
好吧?
-好的  -好的
Okay. Okay.